<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My tech posts on MJT</title>
    <link>/posts/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My tech posts on MJT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 18:34:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Email `IE` grandpa of messaging</title>
      <link>/posts/tech/email-grandpa-of-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 05:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech/email-grandpa-of-messaging/</guid>
      <description>We all have been getting email, sending email, some simple ones, some fancy html ones&amp;hellip; Recently I tried to create responsive email for work and here&amp;rsquo;s my journey of creating an email.
First I tried to use MJML tool, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t change email&amp;rsquo;s main content width&amp;hellip; mjml takes 600px width by default and our design has 800px, also had to change css styles, didn&amp;rsquo;t dive much into docs and example, i tried being hackies and after failing, I thought, whatever I know html/css3 pretty well, I will do it without using any tool, the pride of me awaken ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resize or new partition for /var</title>
      <link>/posts/tech/resize-or-new-partition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 15:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech/resize-or-new-partition/</guid>
      <description>why? Thought /var wouldnt need more than 5G of space, so I foolishly created partition of only 5G and set /var to it. You know when you got new ssd with only 256G space, you try to act cool and think you can optimize but the thing is I am too lazy to optimize everytime 😅 😅 I checked my old hard disk the HDD and found out, /var was given 21G space and it was 15G filled already&amp;hellip; Then my adrenaline rush of need to resize came strong and I am changing this state while writting this blog 😅 , if something goes wrong, I would be needing bootable pendrive 😅 😅 /var /var is a standard subdirectory of the root directory in Linux and other Unix-like operating systems that contains files to which the system writes data during the course of its operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Data Mining </title>
      <link>/posts/tech/learning-data-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 14:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech/learning-data-mining/</guid>
      <description>learning data mining
Nature of data After observation, we can get 3 types of data
Nominal : which has label or tags, cant take mean, we can take percentage (frequecy) though eg, sex, taste
Ordinal : Rank, satisfactions, mean may not be good&amp;hellip;
Interval/Ratio : Measure, intervals like age, time, couts
Customer Age Sex Groceries Chocobars Type Satisfied Bulk 1 18 Male Rs 140 2 Milk 1 2 1 23 Female Rs 270 2 Dark 3 3 1 21 Female Rs 160 2 White 2 4 1 27 Male Rs 180 2 Milk 1 2 Type is Nominal and can be displayed in pie chart or bar chart Satisfied is Ordinal and can&amp;rsquo;t be displayed in pie chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All about JWT</title>
      <link>/posts/tech/all-about-jwt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 05:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech/all-about-jwt/</guid>
      <description>JWT RFC7519 states:
JSON Web Token (JWT) is a compact, URL-safe means of representing claims to be transferred between two parties. The claims in a JWT are encoded as a JSON object that is used as the payload of a JSON Web Signature (JWS) structure or as the plaintext of a JSON Web Encryption (JWE) structure, enabling the claims to be digitally signed or integrity protected with a Message Authentication Code (MAC) and/or encrypted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebWeekend Kathmandu 2018 </title>
      <link>/posts/tech/wwktm-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 16:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech/wwktm-2018/</guid>
      <description>I will write about web weekend 2018 here (hopefully someday)
Facts and Figures ~300 attendees in the whole event Representatives from &amp;gt;55 different companies in Nepal 11 different nationalities at the conference 10% female attendees 😢 8 wwktm sponsored attendees (exluding other partial discounts) 80 people hiked 1 HUGE bag of trash collected from the trail. We like our trails clean. Web Weekend Kathmandu is happening this year on septmember. Visit past wwktm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to HUGO</title>
      <link>/posts/tech/using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech/using-hugo/</guid>
      <description>From this day, I am using HUGO, switched from Wordpress to my own Angularjs SPA static site to HUGO&amp;hellip; yay
I did thought, &amp;ldquo;Oh why not just use medium.com and get rid of all setting up hassles&amp;rdquo;, then god spoke with this message from medium.com At that point, I realised, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t host my amazing articles ( :P ) in others&amp;rsquo; platform :D :D
Hugo Hugo is open-source static site builder written in Go lang.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
